Alan McClenaghan

Summary

A 5x Salesforce professional with experience of Digital Print and Web Design using HTML, CSS & JavaScript. Alan first encountered Salesforce while working as a Junior Software Tester where he worked alongside Developers to debug web app functionalities. He then joined Revolent Group as a Salesforce Developer, learning both Admin and Developer skills. He gained hands-on experience on the Revols for Good programme, helping develop a Salesforce for Non-Profits project environment. Alan is currently working for Atamis, providing Salesforce procurement software for the public and private sectors, and collaborating with clients to design and deliver bespoke customisations.



Key skills and attributes

- Org and User Setup
- Security and Access
- Data Modelling and Management
- Sales and Marketing Apps
- Service and Support Apps
- Reports and Dashboards

- User Interface and Visualforce
- Business Logic and Automation
- Flows and LWC
- Apex, SOQL, SOSL and DML
- Testing and Debugging
- Environments and Deployment
- Adobe Creative Suite (10+ years)
- HTML (6 years)
- CSS (6 years)
- JavaScript and React
 - Bootstrap

Education and qualifications

Salesforce Experience Cloud Consultant Certified London / 2023

Salesforce Advanced Administrator Certified London / 2023

Salesforce Platform Developer | Certified London / 2020

Salesforce Platform App Builder Certified London / 2020

Salesforce Administrator Certified London / 2020

Copado Administrator Certified London / 2020

Copado Developer Certified London / 2020

React Developer (Nanodegree) Udacity / 2019

Front End Web Development (Techdegree) Treehouse / 2018

NVQ Level 4 in Newspaper Journalism Belfast Institute / 2005 – 2006

MA English (Creative Writing) Queen's University of Belfast / 2000 – 2002

BA English Queen's University of Belfast / 1997 – 2000

Alan McClenaghan

Experience

Configuration Specialist | Atamis

June 2023 - Present

- Working with and customising Salesforce procurement software for government agencies.
- Communicating with clients to understand requirements and scope.
- Designing and implementing customisations to client specifications.
- Creating and customising Salesforce objects and fields, page layouts and Lightning Layouts.
- Creating Flows, approval processes and other automations to deliver client requirements.
- Maintaining sandboxes and using change sets to deploy changes to Production environments.

Salesforce Developer | Revolent Group

February 2020 – June 2023

- Creating Salesforce Developer Orgs to increase Salesforce capabilities with the likes of Flow Builder and Lightning Web Components.
- Reports and Dashboards.
- Security and Access.
- Workflow and Process Automation.
- Data Modelling Objects.
- Development environments.
- Salesforce & Copado certified.

Salesforce Consultant | Atamis

June 2021 - June 2023

Made permanent (See above).

Salesforce Developer | Client Pro Bono Project – Migrant Leaders

September 2020 – March 2021

- Communicating with clients to understand project requirements and scope.
- Creating documentation to help plan and track the project.
- Designing and implementing project data model.
- Working with and customising Salesforce Non-profit Success Pack.
- Creating and customising Salesforce objects and fields.

Alan McClenaghan

Junior Software Tester | Wunderman Thompson Commerce

August 2019 - December 2019

- Testing Salesforce and Shopify components of commerce websites to ensure they worked as intended and integrated correctly with other systems.
- Worked alongside Salesforce and Shopify Developers.
- Provided bug reports & diagnostics to Developers for any corrections to be made.

Designer | Kadium Publishing

January 2011 – February 2019

- Worked on serval high-profile technology magazines including Networking+, 3 international Wireless Communications titles and several Yearbooks.
- Designed HTML newsletters and digital edition emails.
- Redesigned and updated company website using modern responsive web techniques.
- Planned, designed and copy-subbed the magazines using InDesign software on Mac.
- Worked with internal colleagues and external clients to design ads and other graphics for both print and web, using InDesign, Photoshop and Illustrator software.
- Produced PDFs using Adobe Acrobat and coordinated final magazine publication with printers.

Page Editor and Sub Editor | Freelance Designer

May 2009 - January 2011

- Sub-edited and designed magazine pages for Centaur, Incisive Media, IPC and Reed Business Information.
- Copy-edited petrochemical market information for Independent Commodity Intelligence Services.

Page Editor | Racing Post

July 2008 - May 2009

- Designed and sub-edited pages for daily racing newspaper and weekly sister titles, to strict deadlines, using QuarkXPress and QuarkCopyDesk software on Mac.
- Edited and uploaded material to the internet using inhouse Content Management System.
- Worked as part of a large team of designers, sub-editors and other journalists.

Sub Editor | Newsquest Media Group Ltd

October 2006 – July 2008

- Designed and sub-edited pages for more than 12 newspaper titles, each with its own deadline, using QuarkXPress and Scribe software on Windows.
- Edited and uploaded material to the internet using inhouse Content Management System.
- Worked as part of a large team of designers, sub-editors and other journalists.
- Named Sub-Editor of the Year at the Newsquest South London Awards 2007 for designing pages "head and shoulders above the rest".